[
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, Deirdre is planning to perform in a play about",
    "a": "Henry VIII",
    "b": "Catherine the Great",
    "c": "Louis XIV",
    "d": "Mary of Scotland",
    "e": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Maltzer feel about the sense of sight in “No Woman Born”?",
    "a": "It is a sense that ties us in with nature and the human race.",
    "b": "It is the most necessary sense to have.",
    "c": "It is more cold and intellectual than any of the other senses.",
    "d": "It is more reliable than any of the other senses.",
    "e": "It is one of the more primitive senses.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, how does Deirdre convey a sense of humanity during her performance?",
    "a": "through her theatrical facial expressions",
    "b": "through the smoothness of her movements",
    "c": "through her mellifluous singing",
    "d": "through her full-throated laughter",
    "e": "through the chemistry she displayed with the other performers",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Maltzer want Deirdre to stop performing in “No Woman Born”?",
    "a": "He is jealous of the audience and wants her all for himself.",
    "b": "He is worried he will be ostracized by the scientific community for defying the laws of nature.",
    "c": "He wants to protect her from the cruelty of her audience.",
    "d": "He thinks that continuing to perform will remind Deirdre of the trauma of her death.",
    "e": "He fears that her robotic body will fall apart if she continues dancing.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, Maltzer thinks he should learn a lesson from the science fiction character",
    "a": "Dr. Jekyll",
    "b": "Frankenstein",
    "c": "Big Brother",
    "d": "Captain Nemo",
    "e": "Guy Montag",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, During their conversation in Maltzer’s apartment, Harris worries that Maltzer might try to",
    "a": "force Deirdre to perform against her will",
    "b": "create more robots",
    "c": "deactivate Deirdre’s robotic body",
    "d": "marry Deirdre",
    "e": "kill himself",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, Harris fully accepts that Deirdre is human after she",
    "a": "dances on stage",
    "b": "sings her favorite song",
    "c": "smokes a cigarette",
    "d": "kisses him",
    "e": "cries in his arms",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which mythological creature does Deirdre compare herself in “No Woman Born”?",
    "a": "the Phoenix",
    "b": "the Chimera",
    "c": "Medusa",
    "d": "Theseus",
    "e": "Styx",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, what does Deirdre say is her only limitation now that she is a robot?",
    "a": "her mortal brain",
    "b": "her limited capacity for emotion",
    "c": "her loss of taste, touch, and smell",
    "d": "her strange appearance",
    "e": "her lack of morals",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the first recorded human prosthesis created?",
    "a": "Britain",
    "b": "Russia",
    "c": "Egypt",
    "d": "Italy",
    "e": "China",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, Maltzer praises Deirdre for her",
    "a": "prudence",
    "b": "elegance",
    "c": "courage",
    "d": "intellect",
    "e": "liveliness",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which feature of Deirdre’s is Maltzer able to recreate perfectly “No Woman Born”?",
    "a": "her tender smile",
    "b": "her silky hair",
    "c": "her gentle eyes",
    "d": "her husky voice",
    "e": "her slender figure",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deirdre from “No Woman Born” is MOST similar to the robot in the story",
    "a": "“Childfinder”",
    "b": "“Rappaccini’s Daughter”",
    "c": "“The Mushroom Hunters”",
    "d": "“Moxon’s Master”",
    "e": "“I Sing the Body Electric!”",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “No Woman Born”, both Maltzer and Harris PRIMARILY see the new Deirdre as",
    "a": "dangerous",
    "b": "fragile",
    "c": "awkward",
    "d": "unnatural",
    "e": "intriguing",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What central thematic question does “No Woman Born” pose?",
    "a": "Can artificial intelligence replace human intelligence?",
    "b": "Should there be limitations to the technology we create?",
    "c": "What is the proper role for women in modern society?",
    "d": "How can we distinguish between what’s real and what’s not?",
    "e": "Why is it important for individuals to retain their own sense of identity?",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neil Gaiman’s “The Mushroom Hunters” centers around the experience of ancient",
    "a": "beasts",
    "b": "plants",
    "c": "women",
    "d": "children",
    "e": "warriors",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Gaiman claim was the first tool the people used in “The Mushroom Hunters”?",
    "a": "a spear",
    "b": "a pestle",
    "c": "a flintstone",
    "d": "a sling",
    "e": "a club",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In “The Mushroom Hunters”, Gaiman calls the person painting animals on cave walls a(n)",
    "a": "dreamer",
    "b": "scientist",
    "c": "mother",
    "d": "teacher",
    "e": "artist",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gaiman address “The Mushroom Hunters” to his",
    "a": "ancestor",
    "b": "wife",
    "c": "son",
    "d": "mother",
    "e": "friend",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In stanzas 7-9 of “The Mushroom Hunters”, Gaiman 3 times repeats the word",
    "a": "gather",
    "b": "try",
    "c": "observe",
    "d": "listen",
    "e": "create",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following awards did Coraline NOT win?",
    "a": "the Newbery Medal",
    "b": "the American Elizabeth Burr/Worzalla Award",
    "c": "the Bram Stoker Award",
    "d": "the Nebula Award",
    "e": "the Hugo Award",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is Neil Gaiman’s current wife?",
    "a": "Mary McGrath",
    "b": "Sheila Bernard",
    "c": "Caroline Rudge",
    "d": "Kate Greenaway",
    "e": "Amanda Palmer",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "With which artist or author has Neil Gaiman NOT worked?",
    "a": "Stephin Merrit",
    "b": "Terry Pratchett",
    "c": "Douglas Adams",
    "d": "Chris Riddell",
    "e": "Dave McKean",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gaiman wrote “The Mushroom Hunters” for a show dedicated to",
    "a": "Sally Ride",
    "b": "Marie Curie",
    "c": "Ada Lovelace",
    "d": "Maria Mitchell",
    "e": "Mary Anning",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which award did “The Mushroom Hunters” win?",
    "a": "the British Science Fiction Award",
    "b": "the Rhysling Award",
    "c": "the Will Eisner Award",
    "d": "the Harvey Award",
    "e": "the World Fantasy Award",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Neil Gaiman began writing as a",
    "a": "biographer",
    "b": "journalist",
    "c": "comic writer",
    "d": "screenwriter",
    "e": "children’s author",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Gaiman focus on mushrooms in his poem?",
    "a": "They were the most common food source.",
    "b": "They grow easily without human help.",
    "c": "They were the hardest food to find.",
    "d": "Some are poisonous and some aren’t.",
    "e": "They decompose the dead.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Neil Gaiman’s Twitter handle?",
    "a": "@gaimanthewriter",
    "b": "@neilhimself",
    "c": "@neilwritesbooks",
    "d": "@neilgaiman",
    "e": "@therealneil",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of Neil Gaiman’s books was selected as the first One Book, One Twitter book?",
    "a": "Stardust",
    "b": "The Graveyard Book",
    "c": "Sandman",
    "d": "American Gods",
    "e": "The Ocean at End of the Lane",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Neil Gaiman write “The Mushroom Hunters”?",
    "a": "2015",
    "b": "2017",
    "c": "2008",
    "d": "2011",
    "e": "2009",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]

